Content creation is a lot like dating.
You would never date somebody unless you
knew they were kind, thoughtful,
interesting, and a good person. In other
words, their reputation is actually what
makes you trust them or give them a
shot. In the digital world that we all
live in in 2026, that is the equivalent
of having a personal brand. It is simply
how the world views you. But for
generations before, we had to rely on
parents, teachers, adviserss, mentors,
officials to advocate for us. Now we
have the power of posting one piece of
content having the potential to reach
thousands or millions of people all
across the world that shares exactly who
we are, what we stand for, and what we
have to offer. If you can successfully
build a personal brand, just like in
dating, you would actually attract the
best opportunities. And I'm about to
walk you through exactly how you can do
that with my own internal frameworks
that I use daily. Step one, forget about
the traditional way of niching and
actually become the niche instead. If
you've ever heard someone talk about
niching, you've likely heard them say,
"Choose a specific topic or industry and
only create about that one topic." But
the problem with that becomes if you're
known for one topic, as you evolve and
have different interests and create
about them, no one will engage. So
instead, if you can actually become the
niche, the great part is you'll always
have longevity. You'll always have
flexibility. You have a lot more
versatility. And this is how you do it.
It's through my creator vision
framework. It's what I get paid to speak
about wherever I go. And it really does
encompass all of your content ideas in a
way that's super aligned to you. So if
that sounds good to you, let's break
this down. So the creative vision
framework here has three branches. You
have your what, you have your who, and
you have your why. In other words, your
personal brand is the intersection of
what you're saying, who you're saying it
to, and ultimately why you're saying it.
Let's first break down the branch. what
this encompasses your message and the
various content pillars you're using to
share that message with aka the various
areas of your life that you feel that
your message is present in. Now the
beauty behind this is that the content
pillars give you variety of content
ideas but also your content still feels
familiar because you have this
overarching message or philosophy or
ethos or approach that connects them. So
for you to find that message I would ask
yourself these three questions. The
first one being, do I have a contrarian
view? Does my industry or does society
say one thing and do I believe another?
I just gave you an example of mine. I
believe that you are the niche versus
the idea of traditionally niching down.
The second question, what change do I
want my audience to experience? Well,
for me, personal branding has completely
changed my life and my family's life.
So, if I can give people a glimpse of
what that feels like, then I would be
very fulfilled. Where do people
naturally turn to me for help?
Objectively, when I think about my
friends and my family, what do they come
to me for? Not what do I want them to
come to me for, but what do they
actually come to me? Where do they find
my expertise? And oftentimes, it is
around building a business online. It is
oftent times around building an audience
online, aka personal branding. Now, if
you hold on for just a little bit, I'll
actually give you the four content
pillars based on all of the data that
I've encompassed over the course of me
creating content for the last six years
in addition to helping thousands and
thousands and thousands of students to
make this actually significantly easier
for you. But before I do that, let's go
into the second branch. Who this is your
target avatar. Who's on the opposing
side of the screen? You have your
demographic and your psychoraphic. Your
demographic are a bit more obvious.
These are factual. These are what a lot
of your platforms actually already
depict in their analytics tab. So your
age, your location, the gender, the
occupation. But then in addition, you
have what is called psychoraphic. That
prefix psycho refers to how an
individual thinks or feels, right? It is
actually understanding the brain of that
other person that is watching your
content. And that's important because
the more you can call to their pains and
their desires, the more that person is
going to feel tended to, right? So for
example, instead of you saying this is
how you make good content, you can be
very descriptive as to who's behind that
screen, you can say if you are a mom
that is really struggling with time
management, I want you to understand
this five minute scripting framework
that is going to change everything for
you. Much more descriptive to their
psychoraphic. It makes somebody stop
their scroll, especially if they're mom
that is going through time management
issues. Now let's look at the third
branch. Why? And this is your story,
arguably the most important branch out
of the three. Because the moment you
start sharing your story, something
massively shifts. No longer are people
championing your tips, but they're
starting to champion you. Now, the best
way that you can tell stories is through
my 3P framework called problem, pursuit,
payoff. A problem is simply introducing
the struggle that you encountered. Then
the pursuit is how you overcame that
struggle. And ultimately, the payoff is
the final transformation. What did you
learn? What was the insight gained? So,
all you need to do in order for you to
have endless content ideas that fit in
your personal brand is to fill all of
this out. Let me go ahead and show you a
filled out example of my own. And this
is where I'll actually give you those
four content pillars. So, again, if I
was to ask myself those three questions
to find my message, my message would
read something along the lines of
personal branding is the greatest
long-term asset that anyone can build.
Great. Then I go into the four pillars.
And from all of my data, I really do
believe to have a comprehensive and
thorough personal brand that is super
attractive and undeniable, it is these
four. You have your skill, you have your
mindset, your lifestyle, and your
passions. Aka, in other words, what you
do, how you think, how you live, and
what you love. And if you can create
content about those four areas of your
life, there's really great utility in
the sense of building connection,
rapport, trust with your audience. So
when I look at skill, for me, content
creation and digital products come into
mind and I'm just listing content topics
right here. Then I'm looking at mindset
and I'm thinking how do I personally
think, how do I operate? And I think
okay, discipline is important to me,
ownership is important to me. Then I'm
going into lifestyle, right? showcasing
the behind the scenes of who I am and
how I actually have routines in my life,
right? So, I want to walk the talk in
other words. So, I'm showcasing, hey,
you can actually balance this life of
being a creator and entrepreneur, this
creatorreneur balance by scheduling and
doing the batching technique that I will
share, right? So, for me, I believe that
it's imperative that you're not somebody
that just teaches, but you show that you
actually follow through. Then you have
passions, what you love. These act as
connecting points to your audience. In
other words, if you are somebody that
has a favorite sport team, similar to
another person that has that favorite
sport team, you have something in common
to speak on, right? So passions give you
opportunities to connect with your
audience even further more. So for me,
it's wellness. I love to train. It's
relationships, providing for my family,
learning to be a better partner. And so
all of these become content ideas that
fit in this message, right? This message
can be presented across these areas of
my life. Great. Then I'm looking at
target avatar, right? For me,
demographic is quite clear. US and Asia,
18 to 34, an equal split between men to
women. I I actually speak directly to
working professionals, parents, business
owners, and creators. Now, I'm looking
at pain, which are some areas that my
audience is actually struggling with,
right? They don't know what to pose.
They might have grown before, but they
now plateaued or they have a fear of
judgment. And some of their desires may
be that they want to gain their first
10,000 followers or they want to have a
loyal community or leave a meaningful
impact. Then in terms of stories again
I'm introducing various problems. The
first one could be I outgrew my audience
so then I built a system to pivot
content now I'm serving the right
audience. Or it could be that I had a
fear of being seen then I helped
millions of people and now I feel really
confident in my value. Or I had no money
growing up. I sold digital products to
my audience and now I became my family's
first millionaire. You will see then
what's beautiful is that I walk the talk
like everything that I'm sharing with
you is how I grew 5 million followers on
Instagram and 8 million followers across
my platforms. All of these actually
become content ideas, content topics
that you can create on, right? So, you
can make a piece of content that says,
"If you don't know what to post and you
want to gain your first 10,000
followers, here's exactly your next
five-step plan." You could create a
piece of content saying, "If you're
between the ages of 18 and 21 and you're
really struggling with discipline,
here's exactly what you need to do
next." Or you can say something along
the lines of, "If you think it's
impossible to balance both creating
content and running a business, here's
the batching method that I would
recommend." You see how these become
various topics that fit all underneath
your umbrella of a personal brand. Look,
I can go ahead and show you many more
examples and actually do a much more
detailed version of this. If you'd like,
please let me know in the comments
below, but for the sake of moving along,
this is just step one. So, that's the
creator vision. I would encourage every
single one of you to make one and tag me
in your stories and showcase it because
literally there are tens of thousands of
people all across the world that are
doing that today. I see it every single
day more and more people learning about
my creative vision and I want you to win
with it too. Step two is learning about
what's actually good content. Now,
there's a very big difference between
good versus bad content. And if I was to
quickly summarize it for you, good
content is actually audience first
versus being selfish. It's clear and
structured versus being vague and
unstructured. It shares some type of
value versus having no value to the
viewer. It starts with a strong hook
versus it's easy to scroll past. It
takes the viewer on a journey versus
being passive and forgettable. This
table does a really good job of quickly
summarizing the differences. But what is
beautiful about content creation is I
actually do believe it's a science. I
believe it's a skill that can be
learned. I believe that it as technical
as any other skill in the world is. And
most people don't see it like that. When
you think about content creation, you
think about creativity, spontaneity,
inspiration. But I think about
contempered
system. I think about it as something
that you can break down and realize that
the repeated patterns are showing up
time and time and time again from the
best creators. It's not because we're
reinventing the wheel, but we understand
what good formats look like. So I just
want to show you one example of what
that actually can entail and then I
would encourage you to follow along and
one see how detailed I study this and
then do that for yourselves for other
contents too. I am the master of a
specific type of content with short form
and it is called my silent film
storytelling. It is where you tell your
own story through B-roll, sound and
text. Every single day I'm scrolling
through my Instagram explore page and I
will find at least five to 10 different
reels of people copying this
storytelling template that I've given
people and they will tag me as
inspiration. And it is quite a beautiful
experience to encounter. And it's
because throughout my free events, it's
because throughout my YouTube videos,
throughout my Instagram reels, I've
actually given this away because I want
people to win. And now I'm going to give
it away for another time. I really
encourage you to check this out. And
there's actually copyright issues, so we
can't play the sound of the video. But
if you want to, please go ahead and
click the description box. You will see
a link to one of the Instagram res that
I've posted, and you will understand
exactly what I mean. So, if you actually
want to take this seriously, I would
encourage you to watch that first before
you hear my breakdown. But anyways,
let's go into how I've broken down this
video. So, everyone will see this piece
of content and think to themselves, "Oh,
it won because it was relatable or it
was vulnerable." And it's the worst
thing to ever say because how in the
world are you going to emulate that? How
objective is the idea of being
vulnerable or relatable? In other words,
if I told you that, how the heck would
you follow through with it? I would be
the worst teacher in the world versus
there's actually tangible features of
that format that I am checking off in my
brain. And that is why I consistently go
viral with that exact same format. The
first one is the idea that that initial
beginning of the video needs to start
with the struggle. And that means that
you have a visual and a text hook that
both highlight the pain that you've
endured. So, is it that you've gone
through a breakup? Is it that you were
burnt out? Is it that you faced
financial hardship? It's because
everyone as human beings, our common
denominator is struggle. All of us have
encountered pain in some parts of our
lives. And so if you're constantly
starting your content with you flexing
your fancy watches and your lavish
lifestyle and your Lamborghini and you
wonder why no one cares about you, it's
because literally no one cares about
you. Instead, if you begin with
struggle, there's great power in that
because immediately you find people
championing your story and they actually
want you to win. In other words, they'll
actually be retained on that piece of
content. Then step two, you should
always try to use a sound with a rising
action. Why? Because it insinuates a
payoff. you're not going to have a
rising action without knowing that
there's going to be a moment in which
that beat drops and then ultimately that
transformation will actually ensue. Step
three is adding a timestamp. So for me
all the time I will add either a year or
a month or maybe even a specific period
of my life or an age because it
insinuates to people okay there's going
to be a logical progression that occurs.
I am not going to just put on to my
video out of nowhere 2012 without people
knowing that there's going to be
obviously a transformation yet to come.
So, it's going to insinuate a payoff,
meaning the retention is going to be
held. Step four, I perfect the pacing.
This is where most people go wrong. They
think that short form content is always
fast and that they have a lot of cuts to
them. But the problem is there's a fine
line between fast and also too jarring,
right? So, you want something engaging.
To be engaging, you have to actually
read each frame aloud and actually get
through that entire sentence or line
before the frame moves on. So, if you
want to do a very quick test before you
post your videos, make sure you can
speak aloud each line before that frame
moves on and then you know it has good
cadence. You also don't want to be
waiting on each frame too long either.
You want to just be able to finish that
sentence aloud so that the next frame
can move on. Now, step three is quite
important because this is where it comes
together and it allows you to have
clarity on a week-by-eek basis. And that
is ultimately your content planner.
Truth be told, all I do for my content
planner is have three rows. The first
row is idea, the second row is format,
and the third row is intensity. Now,
what I mean by intensity is how
difficult, how much energy does it
actually require for me to make that
video. I would think that sub one hour
to make a video is actually called low
intensity. And beyond an hour,
especially above two hours, is where you
go into medium to high intensity
territories. For me, I always recommend
that you should go one to two medium to
high intensity formats and five low
inensity formats. So then I will
document that. I will put my ideas based
on the creator vision that we just went
over, right? In step one, that was the
creator vision, right? The practice of
looking at topics, extrapolating them
for ideas. Great. Then I'm looking at
studying the formats like I showed you
in step two. So step one, step two come
together and you add the intensities the
way that I have just mentioned and now
you have a content planner that gives
you clarity on a week-by-eek basis. So
this is something that I've done for
myself time and time again. So you see
here for my creative vision, I have
multiple ideas from my framework that I
filled out above. I have different
formats and again I have five low
intensities and two high intensities.
And this is really great for sustaining
your success or sustaining your energy
levels without burning out. Step four,
this is where you start to analyze what
works and what doesn't. When it does
work, you should actually double down on
it and repurpose its format and
messaging. People get so afraid of
repurposing or even sometimes blatantly
reposting their own content because they
feel as though it's redundant or it's
lazy. I want to give you permission to
do this because it's actually really
powerful as a creator. Once you start to
have more successful formats and
messaging in your arsenal or your
repertoire, it becomes easier for you to
sustain your level of success for the
long term. So, here's a really great
example, right? These are all very much
repurposed videos that have very, very,
very, very close storylines. It's
actually the silent film storytelling
format. And you have 22.9 million views.
You have 32.8 million views, 3.6
million, 4.4 million, 99,000 and 79,000.
These are two are on Tik Tok and the
others are on Instagram. But you can see
how once I learned this format, this
silent film storytelling, I'm
repurposing it in order for me to
sustain my level of success without
having to start from scratch. And these
are literally just reposts, right?
They're the exact same pieces of
content. And you can look across the
board. All of them have millions of
views. It's because content creation is
the science. Once you understand the
formula, the way that I'm breaking it
down from creative vision to studying
the various formats, I already gave you
one template. Content creation becomes
controllable. It becomes something that
you know that you can have a higher
predictability for success. Look, the
algorithm is not perfect in the sense
where you can always guess it. But it
does allow you when you study it to have
more control over that process. So maybe
your hit rate or your success rate goes
from, let's say, having one successful
video throughout the week to knowing
that at least three or four of them are
probably going to be good. That allows
you to really increase your audience
size and build even more connection at
great scale. With that being said, those
four steps are exactly how you're going
to be building a personal brand in 2026.
I am not a theorist. I am a
practitioner. I do every little bit of
what I say. And you can see how in
detail I study it. So, if this is
something of interest for you, please
leave your comments below. If there's
certain areas that you want me to create
a more specific or thorough video on,
I'm more than happy to do that. And give
this video, of course, a thumbs up and
of course subscribe because there's
going to be a lot more personal branding
content coming your way. I really do
believe that this is the opportunity.
And I don't know if there's anyone more
experienced to actually teach it. So,
I'm super excited to do this for you
guys and I can't wait to see all of your
guys' wins.